And welcome back to Jupyter Lab, one of my very favorite places to be.
주피터 연구소에 잘 오셨습니다 제가 가장 좋아하는 곳이죠
When Jupyter Lab sprung up on your screen, you will probably arrive at this place the root directory
주피터 랩이 화면에 등장했을 때 여러분은 아마도 이곳에 도달하게 될 겁니다 루트 디렉터리요
with all eight weeks of our work.
작업한 8주 치가 다 있죠
You may also already be within week one, which you get to of course by double clicking here.
이미 첫째 주에 다뤘을 수도 있어요 여기서 더블 클릭하면 get이 가능하죠
We are in week one, and I'd like to ask you to head over to day five, which is where we will be spending
이제 첫째 주입니다 5일째를 맞아 앞으로 몇 분간 함께해 주세요
the next few moments.
HRMH
So as I say, the business challenge that I have in store for you is to build on what we already built
말씀드렸듯이 제가 준비한 비즈니스 도전은 첫날 이미 만든 걸 기반으로 구축하는
in day one, to create a brochure for a company by scraping the web, finding out more about the company,
겁니다 회사를 위한 책자를 만드는 거죠 웹을 긁어 회사에 대해 더 많은 걸 알아내 그걸
and using that for our brochure.
책자에 사용해서요
Um, and if you do encounter any problems with this, please do reach out to me.
혹시 문제가 생기면 저한테 연락 주세요
But if possible, you should be executing this while I speak.
가능하다면 제가 말하는 동안 이걸 실행하세요
Or maybe afterwards come back in and go through it.
아니면 나중에 다시 와서 살펴보거나요
And the trick is to come in and add in some print statements and really convince yourself that you're
비법은 print문을 추가하는 겁니다 모든 시점에서 일어나는 일에 대해
confident with what's going on at every point.
자신 있다고 자신을 설득하는 거죠
I'm going to start with some imports.
수입품부터 시작할 거예요
Remember, you press shift and enter to run that, um, if you have any problems with these imports?
시프트와 엔터를 눌러야 실행할 수 있어요 수입에 문제가 생기면요
The most likely explanation is that somehow you're not running in an activated environment.
가장 그럴듯한 설명은 활성화된 환경에서 실행되고 있지 않다는 거죠
JupyterLab was brought up in an activated environment.
유피터랩은 활성화 환경에서 시작됐어요
Check to see whether Lmms is in the prompt, in your in your terminal window or in your Anaconda prompt.
Lmm이 프롬프트에 있는지 확인하세요 터미널 창이나 아나콘다 프롬프트에 있는지요
And if not, then start that part again and look at the readme if you need help on that.
그게 아니라면 그 부분을 다시 시작하고 도움이 필요하면 읽기를 보세요
Uh, it's possible you might also, in some situations, need to restart the Python process which sits
어떤 상황에서는 파이썬 프로세스를 다시 시작해야 할 수도 있습니다 커널이라고
behind this, uh, which is known as the kernel.
알려진 이 뒤에 있는 것이죠
And to do that you go to the kernel menu and you say restart kernel and clear outputs of all cells.
커널 메뉴로 가서 커널을 재시작하라고 하면 모든 셀의 출력이 나오죠
And you simply start this notebook again and here we go again.
이 공책을 다시 시작하면 다시 시작이네요
We'll run the import a second time.
다시 import를 실행할게요.
All right.
좋아요
Now we're going to initialize and set things up.
이제 초기화하고 셋업할게요
We're going to load in our dot env file.
.Infile을 로드할 거예요
And we're just going to check that the key looks good.
열쇠가 잘 있는지 확인할게요
Uh and it does for me.
저한텐 그래요
And hopefully it's looked good for you as well.
당신도 좋아 보였으면 좋겠네요
Otherwise head over to the troubleshooting notebook to figure out what's going on.
아니면 문제를 해결하기 위해 노트 앞에 가보세요. HDP의 HDP는
And we're setting our model to be GPT four mini, the cheap version of GPT four, which is still going
저희는 GPT 4 미니를 모델로 설정했습니다 GPT 4의 저렴한 버전이죠 이 모델도 놀라울
to be phenomenally good.
정도로 훌륭할 거예요
Okay, so this should look familiar to you.
자, 이제 눈에 익죠?
In the next cell, we're looking at the class website that we created in week one.
옆 칸에는 우리가 첫 주에 만든 클래스 웹사이트가 있어요
And maybe now take a little bit of a closer look at it.
이제 비트를 좀 더 자세히 살펴보죠
It's your second time of playing with this.
두 번째 갖고 노는 거잖아요
You'll remember that this is a class that we create by passing in a URL.
URL 전달로 생성되는 클래스라는 걸 기억하실 거예요
It uses the requests package to retrieve that URL.
URL 검색을 위해 요청 패키지를 사용하죠
It then collects the content, and it uses Beautifulsoup, that wonderful parsing package to parse it.
그리고 콘텐츠를 수집합니다 그리고 뷰티풀 소우프를 이용합니다 훌륭한 파싱 패키지를 이용해서 파싱을 하죠
There's something different here.
뭔가 달라요
We not only parse in the title and the contents and strip out some of the junk that we don't need,
제목과 내용을 분석하고 필요 없는 건 제거할 뿐 아니라 이 페이지에서
but we also gather any links that are referred to on this page, and we collect those links in something
참조되는 모든 링크도 모아요 셀프.링크스라는 곳에서 그런 링크들을 모아요
So we're going to store all of our links in there.
모든 링크를 여기에 저장할 거예요
And this little line here hopefully because we just went through an AST zero one preview for for some,
여기 이 줄에 대해 말하자면 AST 01 프리뷰를 봤기 때문에 아, 아니에요
We asked, uh, sorry, uh, GPT four with canvas to explain some of this.
죄송합니다 GPT 4에 캔버스와 함께 설명해 달라고 요청했어요
So maybe this is now very familiar to you.
이제 아주 익숙해지셨을 거예요
Uh, and then we're going to have a method, getcontents, which is going to describe what this web
그리고 getcontent라는 메서드가 있는데 이 웹 페이지가 하는 일을 설명해줄
page does.
거예요
So let's run that.
실행해 보죠
So let's now again do, uh, what we did before editor is website.
이제 편집기 전에 했던 걸 다시 해보죠 웹사이트
Edward Dunham.
에드워드 더넘요
Com my wonderful website.
제 멋진 웹사이트에 연락하세요
That's very simplistic, but it's a good test for us now.
아주 단순하지만 우리에겐 좋은 시험이죠
And let's print print ad dot get contents.
print- ad. get 콘텐츠라고 입력하죠
Remember last time we printed just the title and the body?
지난번엔 제목과 몸만 인쇄했잖아요
Let's see what we get.
get get을 해 보죠
So now we do that.
이제 그렇게 하죠
What we get is again the title and we get the body.
Get it의 제목과 차체를 얻었어요
But hopefully we're going to get something else as well.
다른 것도 잡히면 좋겠네요 Get up
Uh, we're also Uh, can I get.
Get it, get it, get get it, get it, get, get, get, get, it, it
Well, we get the title and the contents all in one long string as part of Getcontents.
Getcontentents의 일부로 제목과 내용 전부를 긴 문자열에 담았어요
But the other thing that I want to look at then is I want to look at what is editor dot links.
여기서 또 살펴볼 것은 Editor. links가 무엇인가 하는 건데요
Let's see what this has.
뭐가 있나 보죠
And now you'll see that in this links variable we now have all of the links that you'll find on my web
이제 이 링크 변수에 이제 모든 링크가 있는 걸 보실 수 있습니다 제 웹 페이지에서 찾으실
page.
수 있죠
Uh, it might be easier if I don't have the print.
프린트가 없으면 더 쉬울 것 같아요
If I just do it this way.
이렇게 하면 돼요
We'll get them listed out there.
Get up 목록에 올릴게요
That's easier, isn't it?
그게 더 쉽죠?
So there they are.
저기 있네요
Here are all of the links that you'll find on my web page.
제 웹페이지에서 찾을 수 있는 링크들이에요
And they're now being stored in this variable links.
이 변수 링크에 저장되고 있어요
Hopefully that's clear to you.
잘 아셨길 바라요
All right.
좋아요
Now if we're building a company brochure and we want to provide a web page and we want it to use that
회사 브로슈어를 제작하는데 웹페이지를 제공하고 싶고 그걸 이용해 정보를
to gather more information, we want it to follow some of these links to figure out how it can.
더 모으고 싶다면 이런 링크를 따라가서 어떻게 가능한지 알아내야죠
It can collect more information from them.
정보를 더 수집할 수 있어요
But not all of these links are going to be relevant.
하지만 모든 링크가 관련 있는 건 아니에요
Some of these links are going to be red herrings, like this thing here, which is probably from from
이 링크들 중 일부는 주의를 끄는 것일 수 있습니다. 여기 이것처럼요. 아마 포함되어
one of the, uh, The analytics tags that's included.
있는 분석 태그 중 하나에서 나온 것일 거예요.
Or there are some other things here like that's going to be irrelevant.
아니면 관련 없는 다른 것들도 있어요
Now it's going to be really hard for us to write code to figure out whether or not a link is relevant
이제 코드를 작성하는 게 정말 어려워지겠네요 판매 책자 생성에 링크가
for the purposes of generating a sales brochure.
관련 있는지 알아보기 위해서요
That's actually really hard.
정말 어렵네요
The other thing we might want to do is take a link to something like slash about and replace it with
또 다른 방법은 슬래시 어바웃 같은 것에 링크를 걸고 전체 URL로
a full URL as well.
바꾸는 거예요
And maybe that's easier to do with code, but it's still not a not a simple task by any means.
코드로 하면 더 쉬울지 몰라도 결코 간단한 작업은 아니에요
The combined code to try and figure out which of these links are relevant and what's the full, full
어떤 링크가 관련 있는지 알아내기 위한 코드죠 호스트를 포함해
URL, including the the host.
전체 URL 말이에요
That would be a lot of coding, but of course, it turns out that's the kind of thing that GPT four
코딩이 엄청 많겠지만 GPT for 미니가 아주 잘 할
mini would be very good at doing for us.
수 있는 작업인 것 같아요
We could just ask it to do that as a task.
그걸 작업으로 요청할 수 있어요
It's an example of taking a sort of nuanced, complicated task, and rather than trying to hand code
미묘하고 복잡한 작업을 손으로 코드화하는 대신
it, we can just ship it off to a frontier model and say, do this for us, and that's what we're going
프론티어 모델로 보내 작업을 지시하는 거죠 다음 비디오에서
to do, and we're going to do that in the next video.
할 거예요